You've completely made that your own.
Yeah. I'm itching to use it in actual combat.
Hey, I've got a question for you.
What'd you think of the demons?
Well... how should I put it?
They're definitely strong,
but they're not all that scary.
When we first encountered them,
rumor and legend dominated my impression,
but the more I learned,
the less terrifying they became.
No matter how powerful they may be,
they ultimately aren't much different from us,
so they're not something to fear.
Is that what you mean?
Yeah, that. That's exactly it.
What is it? What's up?
Nothing. I was just considering maybe
you and I do think alike after all.
Ugh, you're creeping me out.
So that contributed to his decision.
You let the female demon go?!
Y-Yeah.
After I explicitly told you not to?!
A lot happened on our end, okay?
Damn it. I wasn't counting on this.
I mean, she didn't seem like
such a bad person.
If she were truly a threat,
Theron never would've let her get away.
Perhaps three centuries of temporary peace
has changed humanoids and demons alike.
Oh, there you are.
Are you two feeling better already?
Yeah. The doctor gave us
clean bills of health.
We could get right back in the fray!
I wasn't particularly injured.
I got a lot of rest, so I'm fine now.
I see. You both did well.
I'm so glad you both survived.
Thank you.
It was no big deal. Really.
S-Seriously. Don't be so dramatic.
Well, this is irritating to watch.
Good day, Kyle. Dad's in the back.
Thanks.
Um, Sildonia, there's something
I'd like to discuss with you.
Fine.
So, what do you wish to discuss?
R-Right! Um, you see...
Looks like you've recovered.
In spite of the exhaustion from
someone's unreasonable request, yes.
I hear you're leaving tomorrow.
Yeah. That's the plan.
I'd like to give you a parting gift.
Sheaths for your blade
and the Holy Sword Rand.
Since you gave me a ton of mithril
and all, I made these to practice.
I appreciate it.
Sildonia isn't fond of cheap sheaths.
You've done a lot for me.
I won't waste the mithril you provided.
Sildonia...
Are you really leaving?
Indeed. According to Kyle, we depart tomorrow.
Um, do you think that maybe...
you could stay here with me forever?
I'm afraid I cannot do that.
Where Kyle goes, I must follow.
Oh, but please.
I'd love for you to teach me more things.
Goh...
Never fear. I have taught you
all you need to know.
With Kyle's patronage, you will be able
to complete the golem on your own.
I see. So you can't stay, huh?
Do not take it personally.
At present, I belong to Kyle.
What is it?
Er, it's nothing...
I understand.
I'll let it go. All of it.
What?
I'm not sure what you mean,
but you have potential.
Keep devoting yourself to your craft.
Thank you.
Ah, Kyle! Have you concluded
your business already?
Yeah.
I'm counting on you
to complete the golem, Goh.
Okay.
Take care.
Kyle already has Liese and Urza...
Must he take Sildonia too?
Kyle would come to be known by many names.
They say the "lecherous hero"
moniker originated here in Karan.
I learned from Miranda that
Governor Bax had passed.
Glory to Karan...
Governor!
He didn't have long to begin with,
but upon finding out that all he'd done
was for naught, he took a turn for the worse.
Governor Bax confessed the whole truth
regarding the kidnappings on his deathbed.
Then this ordeal is...
Yes. We may consider it resolved,
although one problem remains.
The massacre at the Gargan embassy, you mean?
Yes.
The empire will blame Zirgus for the
incident and put the squeeze on us.
Since Queen Milena has called off her
engagement, who knows what they'll demand?
My head hurts.
I have no choice but to leave
the matter in your hands.
Yes, I know.
Forgive me for complaining.
Don't worry about it.
Also, Gazus has now officially
been selected as the next governor.
Really? But he's cooped up in his workshop.
That's right.
He accepted the role on the condition
that we handle the work while he spends
as much time blacksmithing as he desires.
So that's the story, huh?
He already made us sheaths for our swords.
He said he was practicing with mithril.
That sounds just like him.
Saying they were practice was only an excuse.
If not for you, there would have
been far more casualties.
Both Gazus and I thank you
from the bottom of our hearts.
Could I ask a personal question?
Yes, of course.
Goh had some money trouble recently.
You were pulling the strings
behind that, weren't you?
What?
Threatened by Governor Bax, Gazus distanced
himself from you to keep you out of things.
Unaware of the situation, you came up with a
plan to force the two of you closer together.
You set your sights on Goh,
who was looking for investors.
You didn't even act as an intermediary.
You just suggested to the right people
that there was a business opportunity.
Then you waited for it to blow up, intending
to earn Gazus's favor by rescuing Goh.
Even if I'm wrong, I doubt I'm far off the mark.
I'm in awe. Your deductive
skills are impressive.
However, do you have any concrete proof?
Unfortunately, no.
Well, that's a shame.
In that case, isn't this all mere conjecture?
It would seem so.
Why don't we both forget I said it?
Say what you will, but that was
a rather serious accusation.
However did you manage to come to it?
Well, you see, I know you have no qualms
about doing something so calculating.
What?
If you've got something to feel guilty about,
I'd like you to do me a favor.
Could you make sure no one learns the details
about Goh's golem restoration project?
No nation can know. Not even Zirgus.
If that's all you require,
I believe I can do that.
Then we have a deal.
But do you really believe he'll succeed?
Who invests in a project they expect to fail?
I suppose you have a point.
But this golem would be
a major boon to our forces.
If all goes well, I will have
to report it to the kingdom.
Well, I don't expect you to hide it forever.
Just avoid attracting attention
until his research is on track
and implementation is in sight.
I see.
It's all right.
Even if it takes a while,
it won't be more than three years.
There'll be no need
to keep it secret after that.
Um...
Don't make that face.
I'd rather see you smiling instead.
I'm amazed you can say that
after threatening me.
You're absolutely right.
But you look much better now
than when you were just surviving.
What?
Forgive the odd question,
but have we met before?
No. We met for the first time here in Karan.
Aw, man.
I never got to properly test my sword.
Don't say that.
You'll get the chance soon enough.
For now, we should return
to Zirgus and make our report.
Perhaps I'll have them treat me
to another snack or two.
That's all you think about.
What do you mean, that's all?
They'll probably ask us all kinds
of questions about our trip.
Now, now. She needs the nutrients.
Yes, there will be no avoiding that.
I'll turn you into a snack and eat you!
What?!
There were already tensions between
Zirgus and the Gargan Empire over Karan.
Who knows how much the assassination of
a key figure will impact their relationship?
We know the demons are up to something.
We have bigger problems.
They could be planning an attack.
If we're busy fighting amongst ourselves,
that could spell the worst possible outcome.
That's why we're working to unite humanoids.
We can change our fate.
Damn, dude.
You're always so motivated.
This is a difficult situation.
We've been informed that
all three princes were urgently summoned
to the imperial capital of Ruos.
At this rate, tensions between
our two nations will only worsen.
Yes, I know.
Auges, Kilren.
I have a mission for you two.
There.
I wonder if Kyle's doing okay.
You're as helpless as ever
with everything that's not magic.
Layla! Good morning.
Hey, Ceraia. Working hard, I see.
You're leaving already?
Yeah. If I see them, I'll say hello for you.
Anything can happen on the road. Be careful.
Sure. This is a critical time for you too.
Don't strain yourself.
Hey, look!
That's...
There. I'm all out.
What?
Traveling by carriage is nice
and easy, but it's a bit boring.
My turn next.
I won't lose this time.
We'll see about that.
Maybe I'll take this one.
Or maybe this one.
This one!
I'm all out too!
H-How did you know?
It was written all over your face.
I read you like a book.
O-One more game.
Sure, but I might win again.
It takes five days to get there.
Let's take it easy.
I'll win this time.
I am grateful you would accept
such a sudden request, Sir Kyle.
No, I'm honored to.
"Demons were entirely
responsible for the tragedy
at the imperial embassy in Karan,
which was not a hostile act by Zirgus."
As the man who cut down one of their number,
I can personally attest to that.
We sincerely appreciate your testimony.
The success of this conference and the peace
between our nations rests on your shoulders.
She's really putting on the pressure.
Now, now. You needn't get so worked up.
Worst case, war breaks out, and either Zirgus
or the Gargan Empire will be destroyed.
Minister Auges, do not joke about grave
matters concerning our nations.
Forgive me. I simply think
we oughtn't be so uptight.
You're nervous because you've never borne
such a great responsibility, aren't you?
As for me, I am accustomed
to visits to the empire.
Let me handle everything.
Well, well.
Climbing from a low-ranking official to
minister with the backing of King Remonas
sure changes the way a man speaks, hmm?
I wouldn't say that.
Don't be so modest.
No, really.
Oh, please.
No, if you please!
Please let us get there soon.
If you please!
Oh, you can see the city now!
This is my first time visiting Ruos.
I had no idea it was so huge.
Let's really let 'em treat us
at tonight's dinner party.
The Gargan Empire, huh?
I might get to see him.
Zirgus insists that they were also victims
of the massacre at the embassy.
They claim it was all the work of demons.
Do they really expect us to believe that?
Demons haven't appeared
in the last three hundred years!
Yet according to Zirgus's report,
someone slew the demon responsible.
Alzard was among the victims.
If that's true, it would make this supposed
champion one of humanity's strongest.
It's inconceivable that anyone
could be stronger than our wyvern knights
and second most powerful court sorcerer.
I will not entertain Zirgus's lies any longer.
And you, Maiser! What's with the attitude?
The Gargan Empire's authority
is being threatened!
You're both a bit too tense, don't you think?
I hear there's a hero in Zirgus.
Perhaps he's the one who defeated the demon.
What makes you say that?
Just a hunch.
A hunch, huh?
Your hunches are often correct, Maiser.
You sure work quick.
Am I interrupting?
No, we weren't discussing anything important.
Anyway, do you have business with me?
Yeah. I prefer to be direct.
Let me cut to the chase.
Will you serve me?
I'm glad you'd think so highly of me, but—
If you won't, I believe I should
eliminate you here and now.
You're too capable.
If you won't be my ally,
then I can't have you around at all.
What do you say, Kyle Leonard?
Translation:
Sho Stifler
Timing:
Andy Ellis
Editing:
Riley Dalton
Quality Check:
William Haggard
Translation Check:
Elizabeth Ellis
Forgive me.
Though we found the holy sword during our
investigation, we failed to acquire it.
It also seems Garnias has perished.
I will gladly accept any punishment
to make up for this failure.
What is your command...
Demon King Ruiza?
Thank you for watching!